그래서 부모님들이 침대에서
뛰지 말라는 거야
Joe, that's why your parents
told you not to jump on the bed!
The One With the Jam
어서 와!
지금 잼 만들어
Hey, look at me!
I'm making jam!
새벽 4시부터 만들고 있어
-I've been at it since 4 a.m.
-Where'd you get fruit at 4 a.m.?
어디서 새벽 4시에
과일을 팔아?
Down at the docks.
You know, you can get it wholesale.
부둣가에서 샀어
거기 도매시장이 있더라구
부두가 있는지도 몰랐어
I didn't know there were docks.
- 안녕
부러졌대?
Is it broken?
아니,
2주간 이러고 있으면 된대
No, but I gotta wear this
for a couple weeks.
침대에서 뛰어 놀다 다쳤다고
의사한테 말했어?
You tell the doctor you did it
jumping on your bed?
No. I had a whole story
worked out, but then...
아니, 얘기를 꾸미고 있는데
챈들러가 다 불어버렸어
...Chandler sold me out.
미안해, 의사가 네 말을
안 믿을 거 같았어
I didn't think the doctor would buy
that it "fell out of the socket."
구멍에 빠졌다는 말!
What is this? Fruit?
이게 뭐야? 과일?
Monica's making jam.
모니카가 잼 만든대
나 잼 좋아하는데!
왜 우리 집엔 잼이 없냐?
Jam? I love jam! How come
we never have jam at our place?
너 같은 애가 장난칠까봐
Because the kids need new shoes.
I'm going into business. I'm sick of
being depressed about Richard.
나도 일을 해야지
리차드 생각만 하는 것도
이젠 지겨워졌어
I needed a plan.
A plan to get over my man.
우선 남자를 잊을 거야
남자의 반대가 뭔지 알아?
What's the opposite of man? Jam!
잼이야!
안돼! 뜨거워!
Joey, don't! It's way too hot!
이건 내가 다 먹을게
This'll just be my batch.
That's it.
이젠 됐어요
이봐요, 무명씨?
Hey, you, J. Crew guy....
Why are you following me?
왜 자꾸 따라다녀요?
일주일 내내 당신을 봤어요
All week, everywhere I look,
there's you.
You wouldn't return my calls.
You sent back my letters.
전화도 안 받고
편지도 돌려보냈잖아요
- 뭐요?
- 기회를 줘요, 우르술라
One more chance, Ursula. Please.
This is awkward.
- 곤란하게 생겼네
- 네?
Yeah, because you want Ursula,
and I'm Phoebe. Twin sisters.
우슬라라고 했죠? 난 피비예요
쌍둥이 형제죠
정말이에요
Seriously.
그래요?
That's great.
I'm stalking the wrong woman.
잘못 따라다녔군요
멍청하긴!
I am such a dingus!
Oh, you're not a dingus.
멍청한 건 아니에요
I just want you to know
I wasn't always like this.
저는...
원래 이런 남자가 아니에요
Before I met your sister, I was a
normal guy who sold cellular phones.
우르술라를 만나기 전엔
핸드폰을 팔며 평범하게 살았죠
자학하지 마세요
내 동생이 원래 쌀쌀 맞아요
Look, it's not your fault.
I mean, this is just
what she does to guys, okay?
Well, thanks.
고마워요
얘기 하나 해드리죠
Wait. I got a little story.
중학교 다닐 때
나도 비슷한 경험을 했어요
Once, in junior high school,
I thought I was a witch.
난 내가 마녀라고 생각했는데
상담 선생님이 도와주셨죠
And a guidance counselor told me
something that might help you.
"넌 마녀가 아니라
넌 평범한 학생이야"
He said, "Okay, you're not a witch.
You're just an average student."
이해돼요?
-See what I'm saying?
-Not really.
별로요
힘내세요
Well, get over it.
좋은 분 같은데...
자신을 탓할 거 없어요
You seem like a really nice guy.
Don't be so hard on yourself, okay?
잠깐, 당신이 옳아요
잘해줘서 고마워요
You're right. I know you're right.
And thanks for being so nice.
- 받아요
- 고마워요
Thanks a lot.
Want to get some coffee?
같이 커피 한잔할래요?
- 네, 좋아요
- 갑시다
- 뒤에서 따라올 필요 없어요
- 미안해요
You don't have to
walk behind me anymore.
- 모니카?
"Gone for more jars. Be back later.
Monica Geller."
'병 사러 나감, 곧 돌아옴
모니카 겔러'
Wait a minute. Look!
- 잠깐만!
- 왜?
- 여길 봐, 보라구!
- 뭘?
It's an empty apartment.
아무도 없잖아
We're all alone
in an empty apartment.
여기 우리 둘 뿐이라구
자기야... 안돼
곧 일하러 가야돼
I have to be at work
in 10 minutes.
All right. It's not like
I'm employee of the year or anything.
알았어
지각대장으로 찍히게 생겼네
여깄다
There it is!
찾던 게 이거였지?
Oh, that's what you mean.
- 안녕!
내가 뚱뚱해 보여?
Do I look fat?
No.
- 아니
그래, 난 인정해
I accept that.
제니스한테 뚱뚱하지 않다고 해도
내가 살찐 암소 보듯 한대
When Janice asked me and I said no,
she thought I was calling her a cow.
자초지종을 말해봐, 어서
Walk us through it, honey.
Walk us through it.
제니스가 "나 오늘 뚱뚱해 보여?"
그러면 나는 살펴보면서...
Janice said, "Hi. Do I look fat
today?" And I looked at her
살펴본다구?
You looked at her?
절대 보지마
You never look.
You just answer. It's like a reflex.
"Do I look fat?" "No."
바로 답해, 반사적으로
나 뚱뚱해?, "아니"
쟤가 나보다 예뻐?
아니
"Is she prettier than I am?"
"No."
- "몸집이 크지?"
- "아니"
"Does size matter?"
이런 식으로 해
And it works both ways.
So you both just
know this stuff?
너희들 전문가구나
3, 40번 싸우고 나면
터득하게 돼
After 30 or 40 fights,
you kind of catch on.
예를 들어보자
Okay. For instance:
제니스가 여행 다녀오면서
두 가지 제안을 한다
Janice is coming back from a trip.
She gives you two options.
제안 1, 공항에서 택시를
타고 집에 온대
Option one: She'll take a cab
home from the airport.
제안 2, 짐 찾는 곳에서
기다려 달래, 어쩔래?
Option two: You can meet her
at baggage claim. What do you do?
- 쉽지, 짐 찾는 곳
- 틀렸어! 그러다 차인다
Easy. Baggage claim.
Wrong! Now you're single.
숨은 제안이 있는 거야
It's actually secret
option number three.
출구에서 기다려야지
그래야 사랑한다고 생각해
You meet her at the gate. That way
she knows you love her.
신기하네, 좋아
Okay, this is good.
All right, I have one.
Janice likes to cuddle...
문제가 있는데, 제니스는
침대에서 안아주길 바래
...at night,
which I'm all for.
물론 그거야 좋지
하지만 난 잘 때
내 공간이 있어야 돼
But when you want to go to sleep,
you want some space.
어떻게 설명해줘야, 아까 같은
'뚱뚱' 운운하는 사고를 막을까?
So how do I tell her that without...
...you know, accidentally
calling her fat or something?
Sorry, honey. We can't help you
there, because we're cuddly sleepers.
미안해, 그건 못 도와주겠어
우린 안는 걸 좋아하거든
이제 일하러 가야겠어
I'm late for work.
둘 다 올 거지?
-Are you guys coming down?
-Yeah. I'm right behind you.
응, 곧 갈게
- 잘해봐, 챈들러
- 고마워
Good luck, Chandler.
- 있다 봐
- 안녕, 자기
침대에서 말인데
The sleeping thing.
Very tricky business,
but solvable.
아주 까다로운 거지만
요령만 알면 돼
- 너희들은 안는 거 좋아한다며?
- 아냐
I thought you were "cuddly sleepers."
난 안는 거 별로야
레이첼만 그렇지
No, not cuddly.
Not me. Just her.
나도 너처럼 공간이 필요해
I'm like you.
I need the room.
이리 와
Okay, come here.
- 이게 침대다
- 그래
Okay. You're in bed.
- 쿠션으로 할게
- 응
I'll use the cushion.
침대에 누웠어
여자가 안겨오지
Okay. You're in bed.
She's over on your side, cuddling.
Now, you wait for her to drift off...
여자가 움직일 때까지
기다려
그리고 꼭 안았다가
여자 위로 갔다, 그 쪽으로 밀어
...and then you hug her...
...and roll her over
to her side of the bed.
그리고 나서...
And then you...
굴려
... roll away.
Hug for her.
안아주고...
굴리는 거야
Roll for you.
- 알았어, 안고 굴려라!
- 그래
The old "hug and roll."
One question. You're pretending
the pillow's a girl, right?
- 질문 하나 더
- 해봐
여자 보기를
쿠션처럼 하면 돼?
어릴 때 기억나
Remember when you were a kid, your
mom would send you to the movies...
엄마가 극장에 데려가서
잼과 조그만 수저를 줬던 거
...with a jar of jam
and a little spoon?
너 너무 귀엽다
You're so pretty.
안녕
- 안녕, 피비
- 왔니?
You know that guy who's been
following me? I talked to him today.
나 따라다니던 남자 알지?
오늘 얘기를 했어
얘기를?
You talked to him?
Are you crazy?
너 미쳤어?
First, I'm not crazy.
And second, say it, don't spray it.
난 안 미쳤어
그리고 파편 좀 튀지마
어쨌든 이름은 말콤이고
날 따라온 게 아니래
Anyway, his name is Malcolm,
and he wasn't following me.
물론 날 따라왔지만
우르술라인 줄 알았대
I mean, he was,
but he thought I was Ursula.
그래서 옆에 못 오고
말도 못 붙인 거야
That's why he couldn't just
come up and talk to me.
접근금지 명령을 받았대
Because of the restraining order.
심각한 녀석인 거 같네
Not feeling better about Malcolm.
아냐, 아냐
미친 건 아냐
No, no, he's not a kook.
말콤은 아주 정열적이고
낭만적인 남자야
He's just this very passionate,
incredibly romantic guy...
약간 넋이 나갔을 뿐이지
...that just got
a teensy bit carried away.
우린 말도 잘 통해
그 남자 참 귀여워
We get along really well,
and he's so cute.
세상에, 네 동생 스토커한테
반한 거야?
Oh, my God! You've got a crush
on your sister's stalker.
아냐, 그저 돕고 싶어
우르술라 환상을 깨야지
I'm going to help him get
"de-Ursula-ized."
Like I did for Joey
after he went out with her.
조이가 걔랑 데이트 할 때
내가 해준 것처럼
그래도 난 스토킹은 안 했어
I didn't stalk her.
이젠 소나기로 퍼붓는군
I asked for the news,
not the weather.
- 안녕
- 어서 와
- 왔어?
조이, 이거 선물이야
검은 딸기잼이야
Joey, this is for you.
It's blackberry currant.
맛있어?
하나 묻자
Joe, I got to ask.
복사가게 글래머하고 잼 중에
고르라면 뭘 고를래?
The girl from the xerox place,
buck naked...
...or a big tub of jam?
둘을 섞어 줘
Put your hands together.
그거 아껴 먹어
이젠 안 만들 거니까
Take your time with that.
It's my last batch.
이게 끝이야?
No more jam?
잼으로 사업한다며?
What happened to
your jam plan?
I figured out I'd need to charge
$17 a jar just to break even.
병 하나에 17달러야
깨져도 돈이지
그래서 다른 걸 생각해냈어
So I've got a new plan now.
Babies.
아기!
유모차는 돈이 더 들어
Well, you'll need
much bigger jars.
그게 무슨 소리야?
-What are you talking about?
-About me having a baby.
내 아기를 갖겠다구!
-Are you serious?
-Yeah.
- 뭐?
- 농담이지?
잼 사업구상을 하면서
내 인생을 돌아보게 됐어
The jam plan helped me
take control of my life.
So I thought, "What is
the most important thing to me?"
그래서 내 인생의 의미를
생각해봤지
And that's when I came up
with the baby plan.
그러다 나온 게
아이 계획이야
너 뭔가 잊은 거 없니?
Aren't you forgetting something?
남자는 누굴까?
애 아빠?
What is that guy's name?
Dad!
결혼하고 싶은 남자를
만나는 데 28년 걸렸어
It took me 28 years to find a man
I wanted to spend my life with.
그런 남자를 다시 만나고 나면
난 56살이야, 바보짓이지
If I have to wait another 28 years,
I'll be 56 before I can have a baby.
And that's just stupid.
그게 바보짓이야?
That's what's stupid?
남자는 필요 없어
힘 좋은 정자만 있으면 돼
I don't need an actual man.
Just a few of his best swimmers.
그런 걸 취급하는 곳이 있대
And there are places
you can go to get that...stuff.
또 부둣가에 갈거니?
Down to the docks again?
잘 자, 이쁜 자기
Night-night, Bing-a-ling.
잘 자...
Night-night...
제니스
...Janice.
제니스 공간은 넓잖아!
암소도 누워 자겠네
Look at all the room on her side!
A giant penguin
could fit over there.
그건 좀 심했다
That'd be weird, though.
이제, 안고 굴리자!
Hug and roll time.
안는다, 안는다, 구른다...
I'm hugging. I'm hugging.
You're rolling, and....
됐어! 자유다!
Yes! Freedom!
이 팔만 빼고
Except for this arm!
꼈어, 팔이 꼈어
I'm stuck. Stuck arm.
Time for the old tablecloth trick.
One fluid motion.
식탁보 빼던 실력으로...
부드럽고, 재빠르게!
고양이처럼 빠르게!
Quick like a cat.
And one, two...
하나, 둘...
... three!
셋!
내 쌍안경이야
Here's my binoculars.
그래, 정말 좋아졌네
강해져야지, 계속해
Oh, great.
You're doing great.
Going strong. IKeep going.
이건 야간용 투시경이야
These are my night-vision goggles.
이 책은 공원에서 여자를
훔쳐볼 때 쓰던 거야
This is the book I pretend to read
when I'm watching her in the park.
- 이건 게임CD야, 심심풀이지
- 응
And these are Madlibs.
They're just for fun.
이건?
This is the log I kept,
recording her every movement.
이건 그녀의 모든 게 담긴
기록장이야
Want to hear some of it?
내가 읽어줄까?
한 줄도 안 궁금해
Not even a little bit.
- 당신 얘긴데
- 그럼 좋아
It's about you.
Okay then.
'오늘 피비를 만났다'
"l met Phoebe today.
'내게 참 잘해준다,
나 같은 놈에게 말이다'
She was really nice to me
even though I'm such a loser.
'집에 가면서 그녀 생각을 했다
이상한 기분이지만, 좋았다'
And when I was walking home,
I thought about her a lot.
It was weird, but kind of cool."
Good.
좋다
So what were you thinking?
그날 무슨 생각했는데?
당신과 키스하면
어떨까 생각했어
I was thinking what it'd be
like to kiss you.
-Really?
-No.
정말?
아니
이왕 말이 나왔는데
키스해도 될까?
That's just something I said now
so that maybe I could kiss you.
좋아
Oh, okay.
됐어,
겨자 한 통을 먹었거든
No, it's all right.
I just had a jar of mustard.
정자 기증 번호 03815
들어보시라!
Okay. Sperm donor number 03815,
come on down!
신장 185, 몸무게 77
자기 소개, 남자 지나 데이비스
Okay, he's 6'2", 170 pounds.
He describes himself
as a male Gina Davis.
우리 말고 그런 남자가
또 있어?
You mean there's
more than one of us?
제발 하지마
네가 끝까지 하겠다면...
You can't do this, Mon.
If you do this, I'll
- 하겠다면?
- 엄마한테 이를 거야
-You'll what?
-I'll tell Mom.
미안하지만 오빠 말 들어
이건 미친 짓이야
I'm sorry, but he's right.
I love you, but you're crazy.
- 맞아
- 뭐? 왜?
Why? Why is this crazy?
왜 이게 미친 짓이야?
이상적인 방법은 아니지만...
-So this isn't the ideal way
-Oh, it's not
- 그걸 알면서...
- 말 안 끝났어
Lips moving. Still talking.
이상적이진 않아도
난 준비가 돼있어
It may not be ideal, but...
... I'm so ready.
오빠를 보는 벤의 눈을 보면
맘이 아파
I see the way
Ben looks at you.
It makes me ache, you know?
이거 봐라!
잼 발랐다!
Check it out! Jam crackers!
좋아, 이 사람 어때?
Okay. All right, how's this?
27세, 이태리계 미국인
직업은 배우
Twenty-seven, ltalian-American guy.
He's an actor.
Born in Queens.
퀸즈 출신
Wow! Big family.
Seven sisters...
대가족이야, 7녀에...
독자야
...and he's the only... boy.
세상에!
Oh, my God! Under personal comments:
"New York Knicks rule."
자기 소개에
'뉴욕 닉스여, 영원하라'
지당한 말씀!
Yeah, the Knicks rule!
Joey, this is you!
- 조이, 이거 너야
- 어디 봐
Let me see.
Oh, right!
맞아
정자은행엔 언제 갔어?
You went to a sperm bank?
뉴욕대에서 성의학 듣고 갔지
Right after I did that
sex study at NYU.
생일 선물로 준 스웨터 기억나?
Remember that sweater I gave you?
그 돈으로 산 거야?
That's how you bought it?
아니, 정자 기증할 때
입었던 거야
No. That's what I was wearing
when I donated.
I'm surprised there's any
of my boys left.
내 정자가 여지껏
있을 줄은 몰랐어
It is pretty competitive. There's
an actual rocket scientist here.
꽤 적극적이네
진짜 로케트 과학자도 있어
Maybe I should have them put my
Days of our Lives gig on here.
여기 전화해서
'내 생애 최고의 녀석들'이란
파티를 하라고 해야겠어
Juice this up a little.
정자들에게 힘을 줘야지
어서 와!
How's the maniac?
스토커는 잘 있어?
너무 좋아
오늘 키스도 했어
He's yummy.
We did a little kissing.
피비, 무슨 짓이야?
Phoebe, what are you doing?
아냐, 그 사람 이제
그런 짓 안 해
No, no. He's not into that anymore.
He quit for me.
내 덕분에 끊었대
그 남자는 네 동생을 오랫동안
광적으로 따라다녔어
This guy has been obsessed with
your sister for God knows how long.
You don't just give that up.
쉽게 낫는 증세가 아니야
자기가 쓰던 물건을
나한테 줬어
He gave me his night-vision
goggles and everything.
쌍안경으로 여자나
훔쳐보는 놈의 말을 믿어?
You're taking the word of a guy
who has night-vision goggles?
이젠 스토킹 안 해
아직도 따라다닐 것 같아?
He's not still following her.
You think he's still following her?
피비? 접근금지 명령을
절대로 잊지마
Wake up and smell
the restraining order.
What should I do?
그럼 어쩌란 말이야?
정말로 많이 좋아하면
그냥 믿어봐
If you really like this guy,
you should just trust him.
고마워, 모니카
Thank you, Monica.
아니면, 미행해보는 것도
좋을 걸
Or you could follow him.
그게 낫겠다
아까 한 말 잊어
That's what I'd do.
Forget mine.
어머, 왜 그래?
What happened?
챈들러가 날 침대에서 굴렸어
Crazy Chandler spun me...
...off the bed.
Wow! Spinning!
Sounds like fun.
굴려? 재밌겠다
아냐, 로스가 알려준
'안고 굴리기' 기술을 했대
I wish.
He was just trying
Ross' "hug and roll" thing.
로스의 기술?
Ross' what?
안는 척 하다가 굴려서
떼어놓는 기술
Where he hugs you
and then he rolls you away, and....
이런...
Oh... my...God!
내...
입 방정!
- 피비?
- 응?
나!
What are you doing?
거기서 뭐해?
뭐 좀 찾느라고...
Oh, I was just here looking
for my... my....
옛날에 버린 샌드위치...
찾았다!
Part of an old sandwich.
Here it is!
날 미행했어?
Were you following me?
그럴걸
Perhaps.
맞아, 그래
Yes. I'm sorry.
미안해, 아직도 내 동생에게
매여있을까 봐 그랬어
I was afraid you were still
hung up on my sister.
그럼 날 의심한 거야?
So you spied on me.
날 못 믿는군
I can't believe
you don't trust me.
Well, what do you know?
There goes my identical twin sister!
뭐해? 나랑 똑같은
동생이 지나가잖아
나처럼 생긴 애가 걸어가네
Just walking along, looking like me.
이게 우연이야, 아니면
일부러 쟤를 기다린 거야?
Is this a freakish coincidence, or
did you know she takes this train?
미안해, 그만두고 싶어도 안돼
난 구제불능이야
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I tried to stop,
but I couldn't.
I'm so pathetic.
네 잘못만은 아니야
No, it's not your fault.
It's partly my fault.
스토킹을 갑자기 끊으라고 한
내 잘못도 있어
I made you quit cold turkey.
미안하지만 그만 만나자
왜냐면... 넌...
Well, I can't date you anymore
because you're, you know....
Wow!
그래도 내 동생을 끊도록
도와줄 거야
But I will definitely help you
get over my sister. Okay?
한동안 나를 스토킹해
Stalk me for a while, huh?
그리고...
난 우르술라처럼 하고 다닐게
I'll be like an Ursula patch.
I don't know.
- 뭐가 뭔지...
- 그렇게 해
Just....
Look, I'm going!
그래, 나 간다
따라 와
Come on.
난 목표물이다
어느 길로 갈까?
I'm on the pillar.
Which way will I go?
- 안녕
- 어디 가니?
- 은행에
-Where you going?
-To the bank.
정자요, 적금이요?
Sperm or regular?
정자지요
Sperm.
정말 할 생각이구나?
You're really doing it?
응, 골랐어
37135번이야
Oh, yeah. I picked a guy.
37135.
Sounds nice.
좋을 것 같다
그럴 것 같아
갈색 머리에 녹색 눈이래
He does. He's got
brown hair and green eyes.
안 되는데
No kidding?
왜?
난 네가 금발을
고를 줄 알았어
I figured you'd have picked
a blond.
- 정말? 왜?
- 몰라
Really? Why?
네가 키 큰 금발머리 남자와
결혼하는 상상을 했었거든
I always pictured you with a tall,
smart, blond guy with a name like...
이름은...
...Hoyt.
호이트!
- 호이트?
- 그냥 지어봤어
It's a name. Yeah.
그런 남자와 수영장 있는
저택에 사는 상상을 했지
I saw you in this great house
with a big pool.
그 남자 수영선수야?
Is he a swimmer?
He's got the body for it.
몸매만 수영선수야
너무 좋아
I like that.
What?
왜?
You have a sign that says:
수영장에 경고문도 있어
'변기에서 수영 금지,
수영장에서 소변 금지'
"We don't swim in your toilet.
Don't pee in our pool."
그런 건 안 붙일래
We don't have that sign.
붙여, 결혼 선물이야
You do!
It was a gift from me.
그리고 아이도 셋 있어
And you have three great kids.
- 딸 둘에 아들 하나?
- 응!
Two girls and a boy?
수영 튜브를 끼고 노는 모습...
애들이 수영하고 나오면
And they wear little water wings,
and they run around on the deck.
And Hoyt wraps a towel
around all three of them.
호이트가 큰 수건으로
애들 셋을 감싸안는 거야
좋다
Sure.
But, you know,
this way sounds good too.
이것도 괜찮을 거야
그래
Yeah.
모니카!
Wow! This guy's an astronaut?
이 남자 우주비행사야?
멋있네
That would have been cool...
별거 아니야
...for a day.
I called the sperm bank.
정자은행에 전화했는데
내 것은 하나도 안 팔렸대
They haven't sold a single unit
of Tribbiani.
Nobody wants my product.
아무도 내 정자를 안 고른대
이해가 안돼
I don't get it.
Maybe if they met me in person.
나를 직접 봐야 하는데
여기 뭐 묻었어
You got a thing on your....
Get it?
됐어?
응
Yeah.
안녕
Hello.
왔어?
그래
챈들러, 잠깐 나 좀 보자
Chan, can I talk to you
for a second?
그래, 왜?
Sure. What's up?
남녀 관계에 관한 조언인데
이건 너도 알지 모르겠다
Just one additional
relationship thought.
Something you're probably aware of.
비밀은 없다!
Women talk.